Excuse me, sir.
Sir.
Yep.
Is this your house?
It is.
How did you afford this place, man?
How did you get rich?
Who the hell are you?
I'm going all over New York interviewing the richest.
I'm going all over New York interviewing the richest people
to help the younger generation.
I grew a channel to 20 million followers
trying to help people with business.
All right, typically in New York,
you don't come up on people's houses like that.
Could I just ask, what do you do?
You ever hear of Blackstone?
Blackstone?
Yeah.
They bought my company in 2016.
Not once, but twice.
You sold your company to Blackstone for how much money?
A lot of money.
My company's worth today approximately $300 to $500
million, depending on who you talk to.
Congratulations, man.
How old are you?
And you're still working today?
I get up every morning, and
I go to work every single day.
Yes.
Are you serious?
I'm dead serious.
Sir, question for you.
Do you live here?
Yeah.
Stop.
Hey.
You're the guy.
Yes.
Yes, sir.
I don't like what they do.
Oh, this year we're on track for over $100 million.
$100 million.
How old are you?
I'm 30 years old.
So you're about twice my age right now.
Let me ask you this.
Thanks a lot.
If me and you died tomorrow,
and you had one more message
to leave with the younger generation, what would that be?
Wow.
Oh.
A lot of people think billionaires live in penthouses
in New York.
But once the money gets really big, they leave.
They move out here, behind
the gates, down the private roads,
where you'll never see their homes
unless you know where to look.
This is Long Island, where some of the richest people
live in America in complete privacy.
And today, I'm taking you
inside of one of the richest
neighborhoods in the country to see
how some of the wealthiest people in America
actually live when they don't want to be seen.
So this video is about to
be insane from start to finish.
So stay tuned until the end.
With that being said, let's
get this video on the way.
All right, you guys.
So we are right now headed out to our destination
to go find millionaires and billionaires out in Long
Island.
But what's crazy about this area
is a lot of New York's money
moved out here.
And they did it on purpose.
They wanted to get away from
the noise, from all the crowds,
from all the attention.
And see, when people hit
eight, nine, and even 10-figure net
worth, a lot of them don't want penthouses anymore.
They want land.
They want control and privacy.
This is where a lot of millionaires and billionaires
come to disappear.
And right now, we're pulling
up to one of those places.
All right, you guys.
We are at our first
house of the day, you guys.
So clearly, they're still celebrating Christmas out here.
So that's got to be a good sign, man.
They've got to be welcoming.
Can I help you?
Yes, ma'am.
So I grew a social media account.
I'm a social media channel to 20 million followers,
where I interview successful people, beautiful homeowners,
all over the world.
I'm from Austin, Texas.
I wanted to know if I could
ask you or somebody what you guys
did to become successful.
Not right now, thank you.
OK, ma'am.
Have a nice day.
Have a good time.
No worries.
Have a nice day.
Sorry.
Have a great day.
Thank you so much.
Appreciate that.
Hey.
Thank you.
You know what?
It is going to be a
great day, even though we're getting
things started off with a rejection.
Look, I didn't come out to
New York for nothing, you guys.
I'm going to find the richest people in this city
to figure out how they built their wealth,
and how you watch.
And you can build a fortune just like them.
So come on.
Hello.
Who's this?
How you doing, sir?
Hey, how are you?
I'm doing good.
I have a quick question for you.
My name is James Dumoulin, and
I grew a social media channel
to 20 million followers.
I've interviewed over 35 billionaires
in the last four years.
And I'm based in Austin, Texas,
but I go all over the world
interviewing successful people, beautiful homeowners
on how they became successful for the younger generation.
Is it OK if I
could get 30 seconds with you
on just how you built your business?
OK.
You're going to tell me how you built your wealth
and became successful?
No, I'm sorry.
But maybe in another hour.
We'll contact you if we're OK with it, all right?
Not right now, though.
OK, man.
Well, could I just ask, like, what did you do?
No, I can't right now.
Sorry.
All right, man.
Have a good one, man.
Have a nice day.
All right, you guys.
We just got to our next
house out here in Long Island.
You guys, come on.
はい
You sure?
It's right here.
Wanna show them the channel?
Real quick.
No, I'm sorry.
Hey.
It's okay.
What's up?
Should we ring or go in?
Should we just go in?
Yeah, but yeah.
All right, bro.
Oh, I think somebody's here.
Oh.
Why are you guys filming?
What's up, sir?
So we have a channel with
over 20 million followers and we-
Can you take that camera down?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We got you.
So we have a channel we
grew to over 20 million followers.
We've interviewed over 35 billionaires
in the last four years.
You can check us out.
We've interviewed-
Listen, guys, I'm very happy for your success.
We're not gonna be interviewed on camera at our house.
For sure, man.
Have a good one, brother.
Thank you, man.
Have a good one.
All right, you guys, look.
That was not a happy
camper to say the least, man.
I thought he would have been for sure, man.
But hey, that's as rough as a rejection
as you can get right there, man.
He said, put that thing down.
He said, you're not gonna interview me at my house.
So hey, it is what it is, man.
I understand.
The reality of doing these videos, man,
is it's not easy to get these yeses,
but we're not gonna stop until we do.
All right, you guys, so look.
When you think of New York old money, billionaire money,
this is exactly what you think about.
All right, you guys, so I want you guys
to take a look at this, right?
The spot that we just got to right now,
these are like $10 million
houses minimum out here, you guys.
And we're gonna try to get here.
As you can see, it's gated.
They got the call box.
So we're gonna try to get through somehow.
They've got a fleet of cars out front,
and we're gonna try and talk to the owner
if they're here, man.
So let's go see what's up with them, you guys.
Come on.
What do you think?
You think they're here or no?
Gate's open.
Look at this crib right here, man.
Looks like they got multiple garages right
out the outside, you guys.
Excuse me, sir.
Is this your house?
Yeah.
How did you afford this place, man?
What did you do to become wealthy?
How'd you guys get in here?
You guys opened the gate.
I told you, UPS.
Real quick, so I'm going all over New York interviewing
the richest people.
I grew to another 20 million followers interviewing
the richest people in the world to help
the younger generation.
I have to just ask you, is that OK?
Yeah, that's cool.
So what did you do?
I'm James.
What about you?
Sergio?
Yeah, same here.
Nice to meet you.
Are you from Long Island?
Yeah, yeah, originally.
Born and raised?
Born and raised.
Actually, Brooklyn.
Brooklyn?
And how did you get rich, man?
What did you do to afford this place?
How'd you get rich?
Oh, man, a lot of work.
I started an internet advertising company.
Ever hear of Blackstone?
Blackstone?
Yeah.
They bought my company in 2016.
Not once, but twice.
You sold your company to Blackstone for how much money?
A lot of money.
Could you give me a range?
$200 million.
And then I bought it back.
So did you have a lot
of money when you started the company?
Absolutely nothing.
Started out in my basement.
So you didn't come from money?
No, typical immigrant story.
Actually.
So where were your parents from?
Spain.
So then what was that one driving factor in you
that told you, I'm going
to go out there and build
a multi-hundred million, not a $100 million company,
a multi-hundred million dollar company?
That was easy.
To date myself, I sold Yellow Pages door to door
back in the day.
And then I rolled out one of their big programs
that they have on the internet.
And I saw them collect $100 million,
and they gave me a $10,000 check.
So I said, I'm doing this on my own.
And why this?
This space in particular.
Out of anything you could have done, why internet marketing?
Why internet advertising?
It was you do everyone.
So we were all on a level playing field.
No one knew more than the other guy.
Like kind of AI right
now, it's all over the place,
but no one knows how to use it yet.
We're all using it, but if you can really
be specific with it and roll it out to people
and just be smarter about it, you
have a foothold in the industry.
How do you feel about AI?
I think it's the most amazing thing.
The world's going to change in three years.
In what way?
In the next three years, what are we
going to see that's going to change more than ever
has been before?
Productivity, insight, data, everything
that we're collecting.
It'll make it easier.
Are you using AI every day?
Every single day.
Every single waking moment.
So let's say I'm a business owner, right?
A business owner right there, they
want to scale to a multi-million dollar company.
How would you be using AI on a daily basis?
Anything that you can automate is repetitive,
you have to use AI for.
Anything that requires critical thinking,
that's what you want to really focus on yourself.
But AI should be used for every single thing that
requires monotonous work, things that
you're doing all the time
that are repetitive.
If you do that, then you have more time
to have that critical thinking, to put your efforts
into something that requires a
human being and not an AI.
Now let me ask you this.
Did you have people that doubted you
when you started your business?
Absolutely.
When I started my business,
it was in August of 08.
A couple of months later, there was a big crash.
I remember my dad said to me,
oh, kid, you gave it a shot.
I'm like, that's it?
So your dad was telling you,
go back and get a job.
Yeah, basically.
He said, well, you gave
it a shot, and that's it.
But you just persevered and kept on going.
What did you see, though, that told you
that this is not the end?
Like, what did you see in that moment
when you had your dad telling
you, man, you gave it a shot,
right?
He's telling you to hang up the cleats.
What did you see that
told you, man, I'm not done.
I'm going to go build an empire.
There were so many people out there, big companies
that we were competing against.
And the biggest lesson I learned is,
I remember I sent an
email to a big telecom company
that we just won.
We're competing against one of the largest advertising
agencies.
And I sent an email over Christmas time.
And I said, hey, listen, my team is
going to be gone for the next two hours.
If you need anything, just let me know.
He sends me an email back.
He goes, you won the business.
Here's why.
So he sends me an email from this huge,
I'm talking about thousands of people, advertising company,
saying, we'll be out for
the holidays for the next two
weeks.
If you need to reach someone, send an email,
and we'll reach you within the next 24 hours.
He goes, you got the business.
I love that.
You said you bought your company back.
I bought my company back.
How does that work?
It's something that I think could happen.
But I was presented the opportunity.
And I was able to take
a shot and start all over again.
Do you think when most exits happen,
the company that buys it, they ultimately ruin it?
For the most part.
Because you know what they forget?
The people behind it.
That's the most crucial thing.
The people behind it, meaning the customers
or the employees?
No, the employees.
The employees that actually built the company.
So private equity comes in for the most part.
They think the people are as important.
They want to change everything.
But they forget that founder's mentality
is important.
I think the biggest thing is always running that company
like a startup, regardless of the size.
And when that exit happens,
the heart's not in it anymore.
Because the people, like, that was your baby.
Yeah.
But it still is.
It still was every single day.
I treated it as my
baby, even when it truly wasn't.
And is the goal to
make it even bigger this time?
Absolutely.
So how old are you?
You're 53.
You look amazing for 53.
Thank you.
But you've already sold for $200 million.
And you're still motivated to
keep on growing the company out
to maybe a billion dollar company next.
What's keeping you motivated and going?
Why stop?
Just keep on going.
I haven't achieved everything I
want to.
I haven't achieved what I want yet.
Do you think that there's, that's
a blessing and a curse, though?
It is.
Do you think there's a
level of that you're not really
ever going to be satisfied?
Yeah.
There's a thing of satisfaction.
But that's also what drives you.
So you've got to try
and temper that a little bit.
But you don't want to lose that drive.
The biggest thing is not losing that founder spirit
and what made you great in the beginning.
Getting up, being excited, going
in, coming up with new ideas,
and just never stopping.
Can't take a break.
Sergio, if me and you died tomorrow
and you had one more message to leave
with the younger generation, what would that be?
Believe in yourself.
Always having that picture of something that's out of reach
and saying, how do I get there?
But what are all the little steps along the way
to actually get there?
Yeah.
Did you have an LLC when you started your business?
I didn't know what an LLC was.
I had no idea.
But how important is the entity structure?
Incredibly important.
Why?
That's how you protect yourself.
That's how you make sure that you have everything legally
done the right way.
Going forward now with your companies,
I'm assuming you use an
entity structure with all of them.
Oh, absolutely.
Yeah.
Absolutely.
A lot of people, they think
that it's so hard to start
a business in today's world.
They think there's so much paperwork involved,
you have to get a lawyer.
But all you need is an LLC, essentially.
That's all you need, an LLC.
There's a company that I use, and a lot
of the most successful entrepreneurs
that I interview and know use.
It's called Busy.
And it literally takes everything off you.
You can start a business in 10 minutes with them.
So the most successful entrepreneurs I've seen,
they all use Busy to
start their LLC, their S Corp.
They handle everything for you.
That's what I've seen it today.
The hardest part is the idea.
The easy part is the setup, as you said,
with something like Busy.
You got amazing advice, sir.
This was an incredible interview.
No, I'm glad I ran into you guys.
I wasn't going to let you in, but.
Thank you, man.
I appreciate that.
Really appreciate it.
I connect with all the millionaires and billionaires
that I interview.
Could I get your contact?
Absolutely.
Is that OK?
Awesome.
Guys, we finally got one.
Did you hear what that New York entrepreneur just said?
First of all, he sold his company to Blackstone
for over $200 million.
And when I asked him if
he had an LLC when he started,
he said, I didn't even know what an LLC was.
Think about that.
Like he said, the idea was the hard part.
Building the business was the hard part.
But setting up the LLC, that should have been easy.
And today, it is.
And that's exactly why I tell people to use Busy.
Look, your LLC isn't about being fancy.
It's about protection.
It protects your personal assets.
It sets you up correctly for taxes.
And most importantly, it turns your idea
into a real business.
And you don't need to overthink it.
You don't need a lawyer.
You don't need weeks worth of paperwork
like everybody thinks it takes.
With Busy, you can set up your LLC or S-corp
in under 10 minutes.
They handle all the filing.
They give you a free registered agent for a year.
And they send you lifetime compliance alerts
so that way you don't miss anything.
And guys, I'm not saying this.
Look, I built my own multimillion dollar business
using Busy.
And it gave me the foundation to scale without worrying
about the legal side.
So if you've got the idea, don't worry.
Don't worry.
Don't let structure be the thing that slows you down.
So waste no more time.
Go down and click the link
in the description of this video
to set your business up with Busy today
and watch your business and your life change forever.
Now, with that being said,
let's go get this next interview.
All right, you guys.
So look, we just got
to our next set of houses
out here in Long Island, you guys.
Look, as you can see, look, same sort of setup,
big gates and whatnot.
But look, again, we're going
to be going door to door
in these next set of houses
that we got out here, you guys.
So it looks like we
got a G-Wagon Jeep or G-Wagon
pulling out of here, man.
We got to see if we can see it.
We can stop these people real quick.
We don't even have to go
up to the home, you guys.
Come on.
Sir, question for you.
Do you live here?
Yeah, this is about it.
I grew to another 20 million followers
going all over the world,
giving the richest people to help.
You're the guy.
Yes.
Yes, sir.
Everyone like what they do.
Is this your house?
Yeah.
And what did you do to afford this place, man?
This is one of the richest neighborhoods in America.
I sell robots.
You sell robots?
Sell robots.
Do you actually?
Yeah.
So you've seen like the
silver humanoids that are over online?
Yeah.
So we've sold more humanoids than
anyone in the world.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
Hey, could we interview you for a minute real quick
outside of the car?
Is that OK?
Yeah.
How long have you been a business owner?
10 years.
10 years?
Yeah.
Over these 10 years, what
was the most amount of money
you made in a single year?
Oh, this year we're on track for over $100 million.
$100 million.
How old are you?
I'm 30 years old.
No, you're not.
Yeah.
Are you serious?
Did you come from money?
Did you have a lot
of money when you started out?
No.
I got lucky.
I started a drone business.
Actually, I was in high school.
A drone business?
Yeah.
I did marketing with drones.
It was interesting at the time.
Built drones and took pictures with them.
Do you think everybody's built for entrepreneurship?
I think everyone learns it when they start
seeing business owners interact.
And I think a lot of
people want to be an entrepreneur.
But the fact is, there's a big patience level
that I think most people don't have.
And I think it takes
a lot longer than everyone thinks
to actually mature as an entrepreneur
and not rush into something that
you think is great and amazing.
But the fact is, fast money never lasts.
And if you keep building and be patient,
that's what a real entrepreneur is,
is its longevity and endurance.
So in other words, you get rich slow.
Yeah.
And I've learned that lesson a couple times.
I've had some fast-growing businesses.
And they never last if you try to treat them
as fast-growing businesses.
But if you look at everything from a long-term growth,
like we started in robotics four years ago,
no one knew what a humanoid was.
They didn't know our brand.
And we built that brand by taking our time
and starting at a very
small scale and building it up.
The first year in business, we
grew from $0 to $1 million
very quick.
But after that, the jump that
we had in the last 12 months
has been astronomical.
It was 100x.
But that took a lot of time and effort.
What is your secret to scaling?
You went from $1 to $100 million in one year.
It took four years.
Four years, though.
I mean, come on, man.
What was the secret to that scaling?
A lot of it was going with
not being a part of the trend,
but leveraging the trends that
are out there, such as AI,
to build them into your business.
So robotics is simultaneously known as an AI hardware.
So being able to basically ride
that wave at the same time
and leverage it to was where
we got to where we are now.
When you started to make a lot of money,
did you ever make any dumb decisions?
Did you ever blow any money?
Tons.
Yeah.
You know, and I did pretty well early on.
And by the time I was
24, I was an actual millionaire.
I had the money in my account, and I tried
to build a life very fast.
Patience is key.
You have a lot more time
on this earth than people think.
And you think you have to
get it tomorrow, but you don't.
You talked about that patience, right?
If there's a lesson about money, though,
that you could instill in the younger generation
that maybe you wish you would have
known when you started to make a lot of money.
Right.
Like Mike Tyson made $400 million in his career,
and he blew through it all.
What is the best financial advice
you could instill in the younger generation right here?
Everyone says is put invest in yourself.
And that means even just trying and failing.
Like start a business, fail, because you're
going to learn so much about it
that it's not a waste of money.
You're going to get more lessons from just starting
a small business online or
an e-commerce shop or a retail
store or anything than you will from going to school,
in my opinion.
So it's like fail fast, just do something,
and invest in yourself, in anything.
Did you read a lot of books?
I read a lot of books.
I listen to books.
I don't read them.
I'm always on Audible.
What was the number one book that changed your life?
There's a book called Ego is the Enemy.
Ryan Holiday.
Yeah, Ryan Holiday.
And I felt that was a
great way to start pushing my headspace
to a much more neutral space.
Was there a time when your
ego ever got in the way?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
And you notice that less
and less and less and less.
And then you start doing really well
when you're younger, you think you're
on top of the world, and you
get your ass kicked a few times.
And then you realize there's people,
and there's so many levels to things.
That's another thing people don't understand either.
Just because you can afford a Lamborghini or whatever
does not mean you're at the level that
everyone that has a Lamborghini is.
What's your name?
My name's Teddy Haggerty.
Teddy, if me and you died tomorrow
and you had one more
message to leave with the younger
generation, what would that be?
Oh God, just don't give up.
I know it's the cheesiest
of advice sometimes, but like you
dead and the next day is life-changing so if you
don't give up as long as you're in the game you're
gonna get somewhere hey you got amazing advice my friend
thank you so much for your time and i gotta
ask you though i connect with all the
millionaires and billionaires i interviewed could i get your
contact yeah of course guys i cannot make this up
man we just interviewed the guy that owns one of
the biggest robotic companies in the entire world
you guys 30 years old doing a hundred million
dollars a year he just gave a class interview
that was exceptional man but we gotta keep the
scene rolling you guys and go see who else we can
find out here in long island you guys come on all
right you guys so we are at our next house
right now look as you can see man we're getting to
as old money as possible right they got
the fleet of the mercedes out here man but
look man they didn't have a call box
or anything so we got to resort to knocking
hey sir do you live here yes i do yeah my
name is james i grew a social media channel to 20 million
followers going all over the world interviewing
the richest people to help the younger generation
i wanted to know if i could interview you at
the right time right now sir just one minute i'm from
texas i flew all the way out to the united states
i flew all the way out to the united states i flew
out to the united states i flew all the way out to
the united states i flew all the way out to the united
states i flew all the way out to the united
states i flew all the way into new york to
try and find successful entrepreneurs to help
the younger generation what did you do to
this place were you a business owner or yes i was
okay let's try to let's move let's try to take as
little time as we can on this okay
yeah it's possible so you're an entrepreneur i'm an
entrepreneur what was your main business my main
business is swimwear swimwear i make some suits
are you serious some suits goggles paddles shoes
now how long have you been an entrepreneur
uh about 60 years over these 60 years what
was the most amount of money you made in a
single year i met anyways between 30 and 15 million
in a single year.
How much is your company worth today?
My company's worth today
approximately $300 to $500 million,
depending on who you talk to.
So you built a half a billion dollar company.
So we have about a half a billion dollar company.
Congratulations, man.
How old are you?
And you're still working today?
I get up every morning
and I go to work every single day, yes.
Are you serious?
I'm that serious.
Were your parents rich?
Were they wealthy?
My parents were not wealthy at all.
I'm an immigrant from Italy.
They came here.
We lived in Brooklyn, in South Brooklyn.
Did you have people that called you crazy
when you started this business?
People told me I was out of my mind.
I took $12,500 out of my bank.
That's all I had.
I had a wife and a kid
and I started my company.
It just goes to show, though,
that you can get rich
in so many different businesses
in today's world.
Unbelievable.
And today, the young people
have opportunities beyond belief.
They just have to put it to work.
They have to, in my opinion,
they have to find something
that is needed in the industry.
Whatever industry.
And you started this particular business
60 years ago.
Yeah, 60 years ago.
So focus was important
and not trying to do
too many different things.
You focused and became the best
in the world at SwimSense.
We do high-end swimwear designer brands.
Plus, we have our own brands.
Very niche.
And then we started TIA in 84.
We started that company
to be a competitive company
to go really up against the big guys.
I'm sure a lot of big companies
try to compete with you.
Oh, my God.
They were trying to kill us.
How did you compete with them?
Were you afraid of them?
No, afraid.
We never even believed.
I mean, I'm being honest with you.
We never believed
that we'd ever go out of business.
The first year, we actually lost money.
And this was our own money.
Plus, we borrowed money
from some oil investors.
A lot of people
will come from a rich family.
Like, a rich family
is coming from you.
But what we see oftentimes
is the next generation,
they blow it.
They F up the company.
They lose money.
They go broke.
What's a lesson about money
or business
that you're going to instill
in your family
before it's all said and done?
Like, what's one thing
that is a non-negotiable
that you're going to leave
with your family to insure?
And for all the young people watching,
what's a generational wealth principle
that you have
that you will never
not instill in people?
I believe we have to put
a lot of our money into trust.
This way, they're covered
for the rest of their lives.
Also, I believe that
we've instilled into Matt
and my kids
that you have to manage your money.
You don't live above your means.
You don't stand by
in Bentleys and Rolls Royces
on vacation.
We do all that.
I mean, we vacation.
We take care of ourselves.
But at the same time,
you really need to protect
what you have.
Be good with the people
that you work with.
You need to take care
of all your people.
And you can't overdo it.
You just got to realize
when things are getting tough,
you need to figure out
how to stop it,
how to control it.
And what's your name?
I'm Jody Lorenzo.
If me and you
died tomorrow
and you had one more message
to leave with the younger generation,
what would that be?
Most important part
is to give their word
to whoever they deal with.
Look them in the eyes
and shake their hands
and always be honest
and be truthful
and never try to screw anybody.
You got to keep your word in business.
I deal with my Asian partners.
I handshake.
They do all my production.
And they give me 90 days dating
just on a handshake.
You got amazing advice, sir.
Thank you.
Thank you so much for your time.
I really appreciate you.
All right, you guys.
So we're leaving the house right now.
And we just walked up
on an absolute mogul spot, you guys.
Look, he just gave us
a beautiful interview, man.
Swimsuits.
Three to five hundred million dollar company.
And he just dropped bombs
from start to finish
in that interview, man.
This has got to be
one of the craziest videos
that I've ever shot, man.
It's freezing cold.
It's like 25, 30 degrees
out here in New York right now.
But we got to keep this one rolling
and we got to go find another interview,
another millionaire or billionaire
out here in New York, you guys.
Come on.
All right, you guys.
We just got to our next house out here.
I don't know how we found this place.
We're going down a random road.
And this is an absolute compound
to say the least, you guys.
And I think that I don't know
if it's mom and dad or whatever.
It's out front here, man.
But we at least got to try this thing,
you guys.
Come on.
Look at this crib, you guys.
There's like three houses
all in one, man.
Come on.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir.
Is this your house?
It is.
How did you afford this place, man?
How did you get rich?
Who the hell are you?
I'm going all over New York
interviewing the richest.
interviewing the richest people
to help the younger generation.
I grew a channel to 20 million followers
trying to help people with business.
All right.
Typically in New York,
you don't come up on people's houses like that.
Could I just ask, what do you do?
I build public schools.
You build schools?
Yep.
Could I get one minute with you for the channel?
Is that okay?
Absolutely.
Awesome, man.
Perfect.
Thank you, sir.
I appreciate that.
What's your name, sir?
Scott.
Where are you from?
Originally Queens,
but now Long Island, New York.
How long have you been a business owner?
I started the company in 99.
Yep.
Did you come from a lot of money?
No, not a dollar.
Are you serious?
Dead serious.
You didn't have rich parents?
No, not at all.
So what was your turning point to financial freedom?
What made you decide to go out there
and build an empire out here in New York?
I started with a pickup truck
and a bag of tools in 1999.
How'd you get the money for the pickup truck?
I borrowed 30 grand from my father.
I don't even think he had
to loan me at the time,
but he did it somehow.
So it was by any means necessary.
Any means necessary.
Built it into a general contracting business,
and then in 2008, when the financial crisis hit,
I gambled everything I had
and acquired a piece of property
that I was supposed to build for somebody else
as a general contractor.
Went all in, all chips
to the middle of the table,
and we got very, very, very lucky
and hit it out of
the park on that first deal.
Congratulations, my man.
Thank you.
What was the most amount of money
you made in a single year?
Oh, Jesus.
We're probably doing $100, $150 million a year right now.
$150 million?
And what's the biggest thing
you did to scale this out
to a nine-figure business, man?
Did you ever think 10-year-old, 20-year-old you
had any idea that this was going to happen?
I do two things every morning.
I wake up, I laugh,
because my life was not supposed to go like this,
and then what I like
to call Viking brain kicks in,
and I realize that if I want to eat today,
I got to go out and kill something.
So I get out of bed,
and I go kill every day.
But you technically don't even
really have to work anymore, though.
I've never worked a day in my life.
I love what I do.
This isn't work.
This is hustle.
And why schools?
Out of anything to build,
is there like a particular good business there?
We started with, when I did that first deal,
which was in 08,
we did a run of 10 or 12 hotels,
and then again, I fell backwards
into buying an old Catholic school building
in Jamaica, Queens.
Got introduced to the charter school world
just because I happened to have an empty school building.
Realized that there was a hole in the market,
and we double, triple, quadruple down,
and we're now 21 schools deep
with 10,000 kids in our building.
How important is it to keep your word in business?
Most important thing.
Yeah.
Reputation is the only thing that matters.
Have you ever been f***ed over in business?
Couple times, sure,
but I've never f***ed anybody over back.
Why not?
It's not my mentality.
It's not you?
You know what?
My father told me once when I was a kid,
you can go out in the world,
be a great builder,
build a thousand bridges,
known far and wide everywhere in the world.
You suck one c***,
give me a c*** sucker
for the rest of your life.
You might need to bleep that one.
So let me ask you this then, right?
What did you learn from the times
that people try to f*** you over?
What did you learn from that?
And just how to trust the right people?
Ronald Reagan said it best.
Trust, but verify.
Do your homework.
You own a lot of real estate today?
Lots.
How much?
Three million square feet.
How much total valuation, money-wise, would you say?
Six, seven hundred million dollars.
That you owed?
Yeah.
With partners.
Right, right.
How did you scale the portfolio out that big?
What is your secret to creating wealth in real estate
that maybe not a lot of people talk about?
Three words.
Sense of urgency.
Constant.
Pedal to the metal, no matter what.
Don't ever put off to
tomorrow what you can do today
because you don't know what tomorrow's going to bring.
Do you think that's something
that the younger generation lacks in today?
Today's world?
Having a sense of urgency?
You know what?
If you'd asked me that question a year ago,
I would say yes.
In the last 12-ish kind of months,
I felt the world sort of take a turn.
In what way?
Young hustle is coming back.
Yeah?
It really is.
I think that we may have had
like a sort of lost American generation
in the last 10 to 12 years,
but I see it in my own kids right now.
I see it in their friends right now.
Hunger is back in America.
I'm going to challenge you right now.
Take me back to the most life-changing conversation
you ever had.
What is the greatest piece of advice
you ever received throughout your career?
Wow.
Okay.
Guy that really put me on the map
on my first hotel deal.
I'm going to clean it up.
He said,
I want you to picture two cows,
two bulls rather,
standing at the top of a hill
looking down at a field of cows.
Young bull turns to the old bull
and goes,
let's run down there.
Screw one of those cows.
Old bull goes,
let's walk down.
Screw them all.
Teaches your patience.
You just got to be mindful.
You got to be methodical.
You got to have a plan.
You stick to your plan.
How old are you now?
You look amazing for 50, man.
I'm hanging in there.
Yeah.
So you're about twice my age right now.
Let me ask you this.
Thanks a lot.
If me and you died tomorrow
and you had one more message
to leave with the younger generation,
what would that be?
Don't sell.
Hold.
When it comes to real estate,
when it comes to anything else,
hold.
Be patient.
Don't worry about the chips
you want to take off the table today.
Stay in the game.
Don't sell your stuff.
Don't sell your assets.
Don't sell assets.
I love it, my man.
You got amazing advice, sir.
Thank you.
Thank you so much for your time, man.
I appreciate you.
I got to ask you,
I connect with all the millionaires
and billionaires I interview.
Could I get your contact?
Sure.
Is that cool?
Absolutely.
Awesome.
You get access to my billionaire network.
If you go down right now to join,
you get to hop on live calls every week
with the millionaires
and the billionaires that I interview
and ask them your questions directly.
They mentor you.
So I can't wait to see you
on the inside of the community.
With that being said,
I'll see you in the next video.